# **WILSON HOBBS**

Web Developer & Videographer

## **ABOUT ME**

I am first and foremost a young, passionate creator. I have experience in a multitude of media, such as web, video, and music, and use that knowledge to create unique products. My technical background is in web development; I am self-taught and have been actively developing personal and contract projects for five years. I play several instruments, and have played classical music and jazz in ensembles. My most recent endeavor has been in video production, creating personal- and editorial-style videos on my YouTube channel.

I am eager to work on new and challenging projects, and to learn from my more experienced teammates. I pay close attention to every detail, and if something's not good enough, I'll go at it again until it is. I do my best work in a collaborative environment, while still having time to work individually on tasks. I'm excited to improve myself and my creative endeavors through working with other knowledgeable professionals.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**BEAKR** 2014 - Present

Developer

I developed a platform for The Lovett School's athletic department to keep track of athletes called Beakr, which is still in use after several years. Built with Ionic, Angular, and Firebase.

### MOBILE APP HERO

Developer

Over the summer, I worked to make mobile apps and servers for startup clients at this consulting firm. I worked on a small team of designers and developers to iterate quickly.

#### CHICK-FIL-A HOWELL MILL

Team Member

During this year-round job, I learned to work with the restaurant team towards an excellent customer experience.

#### CONTRACT WORK

**TEACHX** 

2018 Mobile App and Backend

## CONTACT

- **J** (404) 719-3252
- wilsonhobbs1@gmail.com
- www.wilsonhobbs.com
- @wbhob
- @wbhob
- @wbhob
- Wilson Hobbs

### PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS
- JavaScript/ES6
- TypeScript
- Angular
- AngularJS
- Node.JS
- Express
- Nest

2017

2014 - 2017

- MongoDB
- Firebase

#### OTHER SKILLS

- Final Cut Pro
- Logic Pro
- Adobe Photoshop

I developed the full-stack mobile application for TeachX using Ionic, Nest, Node.JS, and MongoDB. The project had complex data structures and view-model issues that I was able to overcome.

#### THE LOVETT SCHOOL

2017

Mobile App with Firebase

Over a several week sprint, I built a logging app for music instructors at The Lovett School using Ionic and Firebase. This data also mapped to a Google sheet, as well as an administrative dashboard, where the client could read the data stored in Firebase in a user-friendly format.

# **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH CAROLINA

Starting Fall 2018

B.S. in Computer Science

#### THE LOVETT SCHOOL

2014 - 2018

High School Diploma with High Honors

## **VIDEO WORK**



**Dear Doctor King** 

In this short film, I talk about Dr. Martin Luther King's legacy and applying his lessons to our modern world.



**Atlanta Streetcar** 

I set out to make this film with the intent of criticizing the Atlanta Streetcar project, but after gathering some opinions from Atlanta residents, I changed my mind.



**I Love My Friends** 

In this personal short, I explore a more sensetive side of myself, and use music to convey emotional connection with the viewer.

Copyright © 2018 - Wilson Hobbs. All Rights Reserved.

Download as a PDF